mtnl.net.in 2019-03-02

# 

                                        PRIVACY POLICY OF MTNL.
1) MTNL is committed to protect the privacy of personal information of its customers. Customers
    when asked to submit those data, which provide his/her identity, MTNL takes the responsibility
    to use the data provided by the customer as per its privacy policy. The policy provides an
    overview on the way of collection of data, its use and security of the customer data.
 2) What constitute “Personal Information”?
     “Personal Information” herein means the information taken from you as customer for
    Identification as per law and regulation and to serve you better. It is assumed that the data
    provided by the customer is accurate & complete and you undertake to intimate any changes /
    correction in the personal information. MTNL shall collect your personal information through
    our designated point of sales, retailers & franchises, call centers and other third parties having
    contractual agreements with us. Such information shall include but not limited to
            a.  Your name, address and other demographic details.
            b.  Date of birth, working status and company.
            c.  Preferred mode of payment.
            d.  Your account information, such as: dates of payment owned and received, top-up
                information, the subscription services you use, and any other information relevant to
                your account.
    Such data is stored in password protected system. The access to the Computer system and
    data stored thereupon is controlled by limited entrant having authorized roles exercised through
    unique user-id and its associated passwords. The user Id with password establishes the
    concerned identify and thus, the accountability. Although no computer system is completely
    secure, we are of opinion that the measures implemented by MTNL will reduce the likelihood of
    security problems.
   3) MTNL may use this personal information for the purpose of:
                         i. Your identity verification
                        ii. Providing assistance in relation to subscription,identification, management
                             and improvement of services
                       iii. To assess credit worthiness
                       iv. in order to analyze your requirements and enhance our services to meet
                             your expectations.
                        v. data may be used to communicate the promotional offers and marketing
                             materials, reward scheme, loyalty scheme etc., if any, related to our
                             various services by email/SMS/telemarketing/MMS
     4) MTNL for the purpose of delivering its services and/or promote its offer may require
            to disclose the personal information within MTNL, its affiliates, parent,
            subsidiaries and to the appointed agencies by MTNL, which are involved in :
                    i.   Customer Services
                   ii.   Mailing services;
                  iii.   Billing and debt-recovery services;
                  iv.    Information technology services;
                   v.    Service maintenance and service message.
                                                                                                      1

           vi.      Market research services.
     MTNL will take all possible measures to ensure that your personal information
     Is kept secure and all related privacy and confidentiality requirements are fulfilled by
     these organizations.
5)  Apart from above ,MTNL may divulge your personal information to :
                   i. Your duly authorized representatives;
                  ii. Credit – reporting and fraud-checking organizations;
                 iii. MTNL’s professional consultants, which may include accountants,
                      auditors and lawyers;
                 iv. MTNL Business partners in delivering and improving our services
                  v. Security agencies, Government bodies, Regulatory Authorities and other
                      organizations in accordance with the law or as authorized by
                      law/Regulatory Authority; and
                 vi. Entities that handle MTNL’s business and corporate strategies, which may
                      include those concerned with a transfer/sale of all part of it’s assets or
                      business(accounts and trade receivable),and those organizations which
                      manage MTNL’s corporate risk and funding function (which could include
                      securitization).
                vii. To any agencies/bodies in accordance with Rule 6 of Information
                      Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and
                      sensitive personal data or information) rules, 2011.
6)   You acknowledge that the personal information may be analyzed/ processed/used by
     other organization on MTNL’s behalf for providing MTNL’s Services. MTNL will
     nevertheless retain control of such data.
7)   MTNL will not share such personal information with other service providers, banks credit
     card companies etc. or their officers / agents / affiliates in any manner which may
     culminate in invasion of your privacy.
8)   The personal information may also be divulged by MTNL if it believes In good faith that
     such divulgence is in conformity with legal requirements or in compliance of a legal
     process or to safeguard and preserve the rights and property of MTNL and all its other
     users, including for security purposes.
9)   All employees and contractors of MTNL, in the performance of their duties, are
     mandated by MTNL to act consistently with MTNL’s protocols and legal requirements in
     relation to privacy. MTNL is highly committed in keeping your personal information
     secure and ensures that your private information remains protected and no outside
     agency(ies) has access to it. MTNL constantly re-evaluate its information security
     protocols to determine how best to fulfill our existing obligations in this regard.
10) MTNL makes best effort to provide secured Internet connections. Still security problems
     may arise beyond our control as no data transmission over the internet is completely
     secure. It is your responsibility to maintain your password/any other information
     provided to you by MTNL to keep your data protected.
 11) You are advised to regularly change your password and to maintain the password of
     sufficient strength to keep your data secure.
                                                                                               2

12) MTNL reserves the right to amend and/or modify this Privacy Policy at any time without
    notice to you and for any reason whatsoever or in pursuance of any modification in
    privacy legislation or subsequent legislation. It is recommended that you regularly check
    for updates to the Privacy Policy. If you have any query/feedback to this Privacy Policy,
    please feel free to contact MTNL Appellate Authority for your area whose details are
    already available on MTNL web site www.bol.net.in.
                                                                                            3
